<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content Quality | Ole Kristian Dyskeland</title>
    <link>https://www.olekristian.dyskeland.no/tags/content-quality/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.olekristian.dyskeland.no/tags/content-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Content Quality</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.olekristian.dyskeland.no/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Content Quality</title>
      <link>https://www.olekristian.dyskeland.no/tags/content-quality/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study in Print: Competition in Prices and Quality Between Newspapers and Magazines</title>
      <link>https://www.olekristian.dyskeland.no/wp/master-oppg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.olekristian.dyskeland.no/wp/master-oppg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NHH master thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beccle.no/publications-2/master-theses/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Awarded 2020 BECCLE master theses grant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published as SNF working paper 10/20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Media markets differ significantly from the regular product space in that media outlet differentiation is not immediately separable in n-dimensions. It is also the case that high effort costs of reading an article may put readers off from reading it, and instead read about a different topic where they do not have to concentrate as much on following along. In this thesis I present a ‘short-run’ model for media competition where the editor publish a news issue in three stages: first they invest in quality through the underlying journalistic effort behind a story, then they decide on the advertisement volume by producing the newspaper’s layout, and lastly they compete in prices on news stands. I allow two long run variables to vary between the outlets: the size of their advertisement markets, and the effort cost of compromise – the transport cost. It is this latter difference between the outlets which is of interest in this study. By using Launhardt (1885)’s model of spatial differentiation rather than Hotelling (1929)’s, I allow one of the outlets to have disjoint demand, they have demand on both sides of their competitor. This allows me to analyse competition in prices and quality between long-form newspapers, which often require more attention to read, and tabloids, which are often easier to read. I find that outlets which cover similar news stories will wish to differentiate vertically, but that this might also occur with larger distance between the covered stories. The harder-to-read outlet will likely choose to invest more in journalistic quality of their stories to improve their perceived shelf-price. Allowing for varying transport cost complicates the matter of product differentiation, but in the media space, given the subjectivity of people’s preferences, and the importance of quality authorship in information-sharing, it adds relevant insights on the qualitative decision making among media outlets.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
